## FIRST LASTNAME

602-123-1234

1234 E. Some Street, Phoenix, AZ 85260

firstlast@gmail.com

### MARKETING DIRECTOR ∞ DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS

Ten years of experience working with marketing and media companies from start-up, through growth, and acquisition. Specialize in developing products, managing operations, marketing, sales and account relations. Able to wear many hats, develop strategy for growth and standardize processes to make running the business easier. Areas of expertise include:

· Market Research · KPI Development Marketing & Business Strategy

 Digital Marketing · Customer Service

· Event Planning

· Contract Negotiations & Pricing

Operations Management

· Ability to Listen

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **4UR Marketing** – Scottsdale, AZ DIRECTOR OF MARKETING

Dec 2016—Present

Directed the marketing, public relations and communications for an INC. 3000 SaaS company that facilitates and automates online sales, marketing, and delivery. Led a team of six employees and budget of \$700K.

- Developed and implemented a marketing strategy focused on partnering with Email Service Providers (ESPs), improving click-through rates, cross-sell, pricing and customer retention.
- Developed KPIs for emails opened, product sales, click rate, customer acquisition and retention.
- Tracked and reported on KPIs with both the team and leadership to ensure progress and profit margins were met and exceeded.
- Increased affiliate earning by 4.9% in year one and 7 % in year two by implementing a new content strategy, developing and testing new subscriber friendly email templates, and a new email schedule.
- Improved email templates and brand awareness to legitimize 4UR Marketing emails resulting in emails reaching the email inbox rather than promotions tab and increasing "open" rates.
- Introduced two new campaigns in 2019 producing \$125K earnings in for the first campaign and \$360K for the second campaign.
- Performed trend analysis taking into consideration profits, digital marketing efforts, seasonal aspects and daily email performance to adjust campaigns and target markets.
- Managed relationship with third party PR company to achieve publication in Forbes, Startups.com, Entrepreneur, Inc.com and other publications.
- Created knowledge base documentation updates to ensure standardization and communication of the 4UR Marketing platform to new and existing affiliates, vendors, and customers.

Bunny Media Services, Inc. – Scottsdale, AZ **DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS – Email & Digital Marketing Group**  Feb 2012—Nov 2016

Managed the operations of a start-up company to grow email and digital marketing products into a profitable platforms and services. Sold the platform for \$1.2B. Managed a team of 8 and assisted the CEO with the strategic development and sale of the platform.

- Laid out the design, user experience and wireframes. Hired a team of developers to build the products, expand the infrastructure, and grow the platform.
- Assisted CEO with copywriting acquisition and retention email sequences for clients to increase to achieve their personal goals ie: new subscriber rate, click rate, customer retention rate, and sales.
- Developed a business plan for investment meetings that led to the \$1.2B sale of the platform.
- Assisted with finding and creating key partnerships with 3<sup>rd</sup> party services in order to create a successful platform for clients and expand in the market place.
- Managed Accounting, Sales & Marketing, Customer Service, Event Planning, and HR.

# **Bunny Media Services, Inc.** – Scottsdale, AZ **Senior Account Manager – 4UR Marketing**

Feb 2012—Apr 2016

Managed the client relations department, and affiliates, of an online training network that teaches people how to create effective blogs that drive traffic and generate online profits.

- Monitored, tracked, and paid affiliates based on traffic buys to ensure a positive ROI.
- Assisted with key partnership negotiations in order to bring our students the best online training network with the best tools.
- Answered daily support tickets and kept the customer satisfaction level high by developing a knowledge base of frequently asked questions.
- Reviewed and tested developer pushes of new updates and provided feedback to improve user experience.

# **4UR Marketing** – Tempe, AZ **EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT TO CEO**

Nov 2009 —Feb 2012

Provided full support to the CEO and team at 4UR Marketing and Bunny Media Services. Managed calendars, meetings, travel arrangements, proof-reading, running errands and taking detailed notes. Learned the affiliate marketing industry from my peers.

- Assisted in planning global *Transform Marketing* events bringing together leaders in the internet marketing industry to share tips, tricks, and personal experiences that transformed their business.
  Produced revenues of between \$85K - \$125K per event.
- Worked actively as a 'Gate Keeper' to the CEO through email correspondence and social media.
- Attended industry leading events with the CEO and facilitated key meetings that led to partnerships, consulting contracts, sponsorships, and advertising.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts - Communications

University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ

#### **SKILLS**

Communications: Editing, Copywriting, PR, Strategic Vision Event Planning: Budget, Resource Management, Negotiation

Sales & Marketing: Pricing, Campaign Management, Customer Acquisition, Digital Marketing